A Guide to the Papers of Franklin D. Roosevelt 1913-1945
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Franklin D. Roosevelt 1913-1945
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
: Multiple numbers
This collection consists of 148 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was acquired through gift and purchase.
Biographical/Historical Information
Thirty-Second President, 1933-1945. Born: January 30, 1882 in Hyde Park, New York. Died: April 12, 1945 in Warm Springs, Georgia. Married to Anna Eleanor Roosevelt.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of 148 items, chiefly letters by Roosevelt to various friends and politicians.
Contents List
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1913 July 7, TLS (Box 1)
  #2913
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Dr. T. H. Daniel 1918 March 20, TLS (Box 1)
  #9324
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Guy Moffett 1918 May 3, TLS (Box 1)
  #9768
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to "Gentlemen" 1918 November 12, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Harry Byrd 1930 November 10, TLS (Box 1)
  #9700
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Edwin A. Alderman 1930 December 10, TLS (Box 1)
  #1001
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Edwin A. Alderman 1931 March 25, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Mrs. Edwin A. Alderman 1931 May 6, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Robert Barrett 1931 December 21, TLS (Box 1)
  #6461
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1931 December 22, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Elben C. Folkes 1932 April 28, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Mrs. Edwin A. Alderman 1932 August 11, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to T. L. Hunter 1932 September 2, TLS (Box 1)
  #5900
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to William Lauck 1932 September 12, TLS (Box 1)
  #4742
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1932 September 14, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to William Lauck 1932 October 27, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Miss Betty Cocke 1932 October 29, TLS (Box 1)
  #2433-ad, -ae
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1932 December 23, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1933 May 20, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1933 July 10, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Mrs. Edwin A. Alderman 1933 September 8, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1933 December 12, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Elben C. Folkes 1933, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Mrs. Edwin A. Alderman 1934 November 14, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1934 December 28, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1935 February 21, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Cary T. Grayson and E. M. Watson 1935 March 4, TLS (Box 1)
  #9786
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Mrs. Edwin A. Alderman 1935 March 18, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1935 April, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1935 May 2, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1935 May 13, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Colonel Watson 1935 May 16, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Thomas Walker Page 1935 May 17, TLS (Box 1)
  #12777
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Colonel Watson 1935 May 29, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Colonel Watson 1935 July 1, ALS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1935 July 3, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1935 July 6, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1935 August 9, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to "Pa" [E. M. Watson] 1935 September 18, ALS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt, regarding letter by James A. Farley [1935 October 4?], ANS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Hampson Gary 1935 November 5, TLS (Box 1)
  #4108
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to "Pa" [E. M. Watson] 1935 December 3, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Colonel Watson 1935 December 17, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to General Baruch 1935 December 20, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Colonel Edwin M. Watson 1936 January 7, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Mrs. Edwin A. Alderman 1936 January 11, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Colonel Watson 1936 January 22, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt affidavit (re H.R. 9870) 1936 January 24, ADS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt 1936 March 11, ANS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1936 March 19, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Edwin M. Watson 1936 April 20, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt n.d. regarding Memorandum by E. M. Watson 1936 May 18, ANS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Mrs. Edwin A. Alderman 1936 June 23, TLS (Box 1)
  #38-594
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1936 August 11, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Mrs. Edwin A. Alderman 1936 October 26, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1936 November 21, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1937 January 11, TLS (Box 1)
- Memorandum for the President by Edwin M. Watson with FDR approval 1937 January 29, TDS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Colonel Watson 1937 April 13, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to "Betting Commissioner" [E. M. Watson] 1937 May 19, TLS (Box 1)
- Memorandum for the President by Edwin M. Watson with FDR approval 1938 January 4, TDS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to William Lauck 1938 January 12, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1938 February 10, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1938 February 15, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1938 March 18, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1938 March 21, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt 1938 April 7, ANS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to "Frances and Pa" [Mr. and Mrs. E. M. Watson] 1938 June 1, ADS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to "Pa" [E. M. Watson] 1938 June 4, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1938 June 9, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to T. L. Hunter 1938 June 22, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1938 July 6, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt "IOU" to "Pa" [1938, July 15], ADS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Colonel Watson 1938 November 12, ALS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Colonel Watson 1938 November 15, TLS (Box 1)
- Memorandum for the President by Edwin M. Watson with FDR approval 1939 May 18, ADS (Box 1)
- Memorandum for the President by Edwin M. Watson with FDR approval 1939 September 25, ADS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Edward Stettinius 1939 August 12, TLS (Box 1)
  #2723
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Edward Stettinius 1939 November 24, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Peyton Short 1939 December 29, TLS (Box 1)
  #380-b
- Memorandum for the President by Edwin M. Watson with FDR approval 1940 January 8, ADS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Frances Watson 1940 January 10, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Frances Watson 1940 January 17, ANS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1940 March 7, TLS (Box 1)
- Memorandum for the President by Edwin M. Watson with FDR approval 1940 March 8, ADS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt n.d. regarding Memorandum by E. M. Watson 1940 March 26, ANS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Edward Stettinius 1940 June 6, TLS (Box 1)
- Memorandum for Mr. Stettinius 1940 June 6, TDS (Box 1)
- Memorandum for the President by Edwin M. Watson with FDR approval 1940 June 8, ADS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1940 June 20, TLS (Box 1)
- Memorandum for the President by Edwin M. Watson with FDR approval 1940 July 1, ADS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Wallace [?] 1940 August 16, ALS (Box 1)
- Memorandum for the President by Edwin M. Watson with FDR approval 1940 August 27, ADS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Thomas Ball 1940 September 6, TLS (Box 1)
  #12711-a
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to William Lauck 1940 September 12, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to "Pa" [Edwin M. Watson] 1940 November 28, ANS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to [Forster ?] [1940 December 2], ALS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Secretary of State [1940 December 2], ALS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Secretary of State [1940 December 2], ALS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Secretary of State [1940 December 2], ALS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Secretary of State [1940 December 2], ALS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Secretary of the Treasury [1940 December 2], ALS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Colonel Watson [1940 December 2], ALS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to [Knox?] with TL Memorandum to Watson 1940 December 23, TL (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Edward Stettinius 1941 January 9, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt n.d. regarding Memorandum by E. M. Watson 1941 January 27, ANS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1941 February 3, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt n.d. regarding Memorandum by E. M. Watson 1941 February 27, ANS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Edward Stettinius 1941 April 28, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to "Pa" [Edwin M. Watson] regarding Felix Frankfurter letter of 1941 May 16 n.d., ANS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt Signed by Roosevelt and Winston Churchill 1941 August 3, Printed broadside entitled Sail on, O Ship of State (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt Commander-in-Chief's Mess 1941 August 6, TDS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt 1941 August 10, TDS, entitled Dinner Aboard the United States Flagship Augusta (Box 1)
  Signed by Roosevelt and Winston Churchill #9786
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Edward Stettinius 1941 September 16, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Guy Moffett 1941 September 25, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to "Pa" [Edwin M. Watson] 1941 December 10, ANS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Edward Stettinius 1941 December 17, TLS (Box 1)
- Memorandum for Mr. Stettinius 1941 December 28, TDS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Edwin M. Watson 1942 January 21, TLS (Box 2)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to General Edwin M. Watson 1942 February 16, TLS (Box 2)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Edward Stettinius 1942 March 26, TLS (Box 2)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1942 May 5, TLS (Box 2)
- Memorandum 1942 July 23, TLS (Box 2)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Frances Watson 1942 July 24, TLS (Box 2)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1942 October 8, TLS (Box 2)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to "Pa" [Edwin M. Watson] 1942 December 10, ANS (Box 2)
- Memorandum for the Hon. E. R. Stettinius 1942 December 30, TDS (Box 2)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Major General Edwin M. Watson 1943 January 6, TLS (Box 2)
- Stettinius Memorandum for the President with signed FDR approval 1943 February 4, TDS (Box 2)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt n.d. regarding Memorandum by E. M. Watson 1943 February 27, ANS (Box 2)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass 1943 March 15, TLS (Box 2)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Maj. Gen. Edwin M. Watson 1943 April 10, TLS (Box 2)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Hampson Gary 1943 April 29, TLS (Box 2)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Edward Stettinius 1943 June 3, TLS (Box 1)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Edward Stettinius 1943 October 8, TLS (Box 2)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Edward Stettinius 1943 November 2, TLS (Box 2)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt "Memorandum" 1943 November 11, ANS (Box 2)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Edwin M. Watson 1943 November 11, TLS (Box 2)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Edward R. Stettinius, Jr. 1943 December 29, TLS (Box 2)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Edward R. Stettinius, Jr. 1944 January 10, TLS (Box 2)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Mr. and Mrs. Edwin M. Watson 1944 January 26, TLS (Box 2)
- Stettinius Memorandum for the President with signed FDR approval 1944 June 2, TDS (Box 2)
- Memorandum for the Hon. E. R. Stettinius 1944 July 31, TDS (Box 2)
- Stettinius Memorandum for the President with signed FDR approval 1944 August 12, TDS (Box 2)
- "Top Secret" by R.E.S. with FDR's comments 1944 October 24, ADS (Box 2)
- Stettinius Memorandum for the President with signed FDR approval 1944 October 31, TDS (Box 2)
- Memorandum for the Hon. E. R. Stettinius 1944 November 2, TDS (Box 2)
- Stettinius Memorandum for the President with signed FDR approval 1944 November 2, TDS (Box 2)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Edward Stettinius 1944 November 16, TLS (Box 2)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Mrs. Edwin Alderman 1944 December 30, ALS (Box 2)
  #2156
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Edward Stettinius 1945 January 1, TLS (Box 2)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to General "Pa" Watson 1945 January 22, TLS (Box 2)
- Franklin D. Roosevelt Autograph n.d. (Box 2)
  #1082
- Franklin D. Roosevelt to Carter Glass, with envelope n.d., ALS (Box 2)
- Draft Telegram n.d., TDS (Box 2)
- Photograph of Franklin D. Roosevelt [1931?] (Box 2)
  Franklin D. Roosevelt with Charles G. Maphis and Henry Morgenthau on the steps of the Rotunda. UVa News Services photograph.
- Photographs of Franklin D. Roosevelt at Monticello [1936 July 4], 14 photographs. (Box 2)
  The photographs, taken by Atcheson Laughlin Hench, show Roosevelt arriving at Monticello and delivering a speech at the west front. Seven of the photographs are original prints and seven are enlargements with annotations by Hench. #9087
- Photographs of Franklin D. Roosevelt [1940 June 10] (Box 2)
  Photographs of Roosevelt in Memorial Gymnasium delivering commencement address that included the line "On this 10th day of June, 1940, the hand that held the dagger has struck it into the back of its neighbor."
- Photograph of Franklin D. Roosevelt [1941] (Box 2)
  Franklin D. Roosevelt in car at the entrance to Edwin Watson's house, Kenwood. Watson and Frances Nash Watson stand to Roosevelt's right. Photograph by Gene Wilson. #5793-c
- Photograph of Franklin D. Roosevelt [1944?] (Box 2)
  Inscribed and signed by Roosevelt: "For Mrs. Alderman with my esteem and regards" #15846